Take a deep breath. Pause
and notice the sensations of your
body.
Relax
Your arms,
feel your breath moving in
and out.
Now imagine you're standing in a
field.
The grass is green, there's
a light breeze, the
air is warm. With
each breath in,
imagine you are getting lighter
and lighter.
With a little help from the breeze,
you begin to float upwards.
As
you rise higher
and fly around,
you see something down below through
the clouds.
As you get closer, the air gets
smoggier
and you realize it's a vast
metropolis.
Surrounded by high concrete walls,
completely contained.
Inside, it's bustling.
Lots of honking traffic,
people everywhere, the sound is
deafening.
You see people arguing in bars
and chatting on street corners.
Billboards and advertisements are
everywhere
touting every kind of good in
service.
It's noisy and dense
and overwhelming.
This is Facebook.
You float back up,
flying out of the city smog
and into clear air. As
You fly, you encounter a sprawling
suburbia.
It has walls and hedges too,
but they're shinier
and newer.
The residents are still bustling
and chatting but there's less noise.
The streets and houses are picture
perfect.
The people pay a lot of attention to
how they dress.
But all the houses
are boxy and identical,
and they're all in identical streets
in a perfect
grid.
When you look closer at some of the
houses,
you realize they're actually just
billboards
made to look like someone lives
there.
This is Instagram.
You fly back up
and want to see what else is out
there in the world.
As the suburbs fade into the
distance,
the rest of the world comes
into focus on the horizon.
You see farmsteads in remote corners
of the
countryside.
You see riverside factories,
you see backpackers
on mountainsides, you
see small settlements
and emerging new cities.
You see apartment buildings
and straw huts.
Sprawling homesteads
and local churches.
This diverse group of people value
their
freedom
but they dream of some of the
comforts
of city and suburban life.
Utilities and services.
Same day mail delivery.
Cable TV.
Corner stores
with all the amenities.
They want ways to make their houses
bigger
and stronger,
tools to make their business more
valuable
for customers,
and roads to connect them to other
people.
Eventually you fly past the last
settlement
and find yourself back in an open
field.
And as your breathing slows,
you get heavier
and heavier,
until eventually you settle back
down to earth.