Take a deep breath.
Pause and notice the sensations
of your body.
Relax your arms.
Feel your breath moving in
and out.
Now imagine you're standing in a
field.
The grass is green.
There's a light breeze.
The air is warm.
With each breath in.
Imagine you are getting lighter
and lighter and lighter.
With a little help from the breeze,
you begin to float upwards.
As you rise higher
and fly around you see something
down below through the clouds.
As you get closer the air gets
smoggier
and you realize it's a vast
metropolis.
It's surrounded by high concrete
walls,
completely contained.
Inside it's bustling — lots
of honking traffic, people
everywhere,
the sound is deafening.
You see people arguing in bars
and chatting on street corners.
Billboards and advertisements are
everywhere,
touting every kind of good
and service.
It's noisy
and dense and overwhelming.
This is Facebook.
You float back up,
flying out of the city smog
and into clear air.
As you fly you encounter a sprawling
suburbia.
It has walls and hedges too, but
they're shiny and newer.
The residents are still bustling
and chatting but there's less noise.
The streets and houses are picture
perfect.
The people pay a lot of attention to
how they dress.
But all the houses are boxy
and identical.
And they're all on identical streets
in a perfect
grid.
When you look closer at some of the
houses
you realize they're actually just
billboards
made to look like someone lives
there.
This is Instagram.
You fly back up and want to
see what else is out there in the
world.
As the suburbs fade into the
distance
the rest of the world comes into
focus
on the horizon.
You see farmsteads in remote corners
of
the countryside.
You see riverside factories.
You see backpackers on
mountainsides.
You see small settlements
and emerging new cities.
You see apartment buildings
and straw huts, sprawling
homesteads and local churches.
This diverse group of people value
their
freedom but they dream of some of
the
comforts of city
and suburban life.
Utilities and services,
same day mail delivery,
cable TV,
corner stores with all the
amenities.
They want ways to make their houses
bigger
and stronger,
tools to make their business more
valuable for
customers, and roads
to connect them to other people.
Eventually you fly past the last
settlement
and find yourself back in an open
field.
And as your breathing slows,
you get heavier
and heavier,
until eventually
you settle back down to earth.